## Briana Showers BSN, RN

3014 Black Hills Boulevard Heath,TX 75126 (985)-974-7947 showersbri@gmail.com

I am a Registered Nurse with extensive experience in the following areas: Cardiac Catheterization Laboratory, Interventional Radiology, Progressive Care Unit and Medical Surgical. While maintaining a safe, effective environment for my patients, I ensure evidence-based practice and holistic patient care is implemented daily. I have presented research, performed interdisciplinary care, participated in community education fairs, utilized healthcare management, recognized disparities, and participated in numerous medical device and pharmaceutical inservices. I have utilized being bilingual to not only provide compassion and exceptional care, but I have also demonstrated cultural competency, punctuality, integrity, and teamwork.

## **Professional Experience**

**Baylor Scott & White Health System** December 2018-present Arrhythmia Management Triage Nurse

- Reducing post operative infection rate by promoting hand hygiene
- Reducing abandonment rate of triage phone calls from 20% to 13%
- Increasing patient adherence to post operative instructions
- Reinforce patient education on electrolyte balances

## Cardiac Catheterization Lab Nurse April 2018- December 2018 St. Joseph's/Candler Healthcare System

- Through teamwork, accomplishing the American Heart Association guideline for STEMI patients (door to balloon time) within 90 minutes
- Counseled patients about the adherence to antiplatelet medications post percutaneous coronary intervention
- Served as a translator for Spanish speaking patients during cases
- Implement ACLS to critical patients
- Served as a nursing preceptor to Georgia Southern University students when they observe the catheterization lab
- Explained medical terminologies at a 5th Grade Reading level

## **Progressive Care Unit Nurse**

March 2017-December 2018

St. Joseph's/Candler Healthcare System

- Recognized pharmacological interactions with patient's medications
- 98% drug administration compliance
- Awareness of antibiotics administration as it pertains to patient's labs
- Incorporated evidence based practices for patient's optimal outcomes while improving Hospital Consumer Assessment of Healthcare Providers and Systems(HCAHPS)
- Educated heart failure patients and their families about their diagnosis to decrease readmittance rates
- Discharged acceptable patients efficiently and effectively before noon in order to meet measures for Centers for Medicare & Medicaid
- Served as a preceptor to new nursing graduates

**Education** Bachelor's of Science in Nursing

2013-2016

2018

Florida Agricultural & Mechanical University School of Nursing Tallahassee, Florida

Tananassee, Fiorida

Registered Cardiovascular Invasive Specialist Exam Review

Carilion Clinic Roanoke, Virginia

<u>Licensures</u> Nurse Licensure Compact

Advanced Cardiac Life Support

Basic Life Support

Memberships American Association of Critical Care Nurses July 2018-present

Savannah Black Nurses Association March 2017-December 2018

**Languages** English and Spanish

**Presentations** Hindsman, M., Mayes, K. & Showers, B. June 2015

"The Impact of Physician Extenders in Healthcare"

Bluford Healthcare Leadership Institute Kansas City, Missouri